yorksj.ac.uk 2019-07-03

# Privacy Policy | York St John University

This privacy policy sets out how York St John University uses and protects information that is collected or provided to us when using this website.

York St John University may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from 10/04/2018.

When browsing our website, certain information is automatically collected using cookies. This includes your IP address, browser type and browsing data. This information is aggregated and used to monitor the performance of our website through analytics platforms. This data is used to make improvements to the content, layout and design of our website to improve performance and user experience.

You may be asked to provide personal information to gain access to information, make an enquiry, place an order or register for an event. Where personal information is requested through an online form, the use and handling of this data will be provided to users prior to submission.

All information collected in our web forms will be added to the University Database and will be used for University purposes only. York St John University utilises third party software for data storage, tracking and analysis activity but your details will not be used by any of these third parties in order to contact you. If you opted in to receive further information that would be of interest, you consent to York St John University contacting you with relevant marketing information. If you wish to no longer receive these communications then you can unsubscribe at any time by clicking ‘contact preferences’ on any of our emails or emailing us directly at [hello@yorksj.ac.uk](mailto:hello@yorksj.ac.uk).

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so.

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to the University Secretary’s Office, York St John University, Lord Mayor's Walk, York, YO31 7EX, or email [us@yorkjs.ac.uk](mailto:us@yorkjs.ac.uk).

If you believe that any information we are holding about you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to the University Secretary’s Office or e-mail [us@yorksj.ac.uk](mailto:us@yorksj.ac.uk) as soon as possible. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

In certain circumstances you have the right to ask for the information we hold about you to be deleted. To do this please contact the University Secretary’s Office at [us@yorksj.ac.uk](mailto:us@yorksj.ac.uk).

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

Learn more about how you can manage these small files yourself and at [AllAboutCookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ "Find out more about cookies").

There are two types of cookie you may encounter when using the York St John website

Provider | Cookie name | Purpose | More information  
  
addthis

| 

_canary, _mpush, _xgcid, _xguid, ana_svc, di/dt, loc, psc, siteaud, ssc, ssh, sshs, uid/uit, uvc, uvc, xtc

| 

Tracks what is being shared and by whom.

| 

Facebook

| 

c_user, datr, fr, locale, lu, x-src

| 

Facebook Social Plugin – embedding Facebook content.

| 

Filepicker.io

| 

session

| 

Filestack use cookies in order to implement authentication and to enable core features of their filesharing application, as well as to better understand user behaviour. They also use cookies to compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so they can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

| 

Google Analytics

| 

_ga

| 

Used to distinguish users.

| 

Google Analytics

| 

_gat

| 

Used to throttle request rate

| 

Google Analytics

| 

_utma

| 

Remains on a computer, unless it expires or the cookie cache is cleared. It tracks visitors.

Metrics associated with the Google __utma cookie include: first visit (unique visit), last visit (returning visit).

| 

Google Analytics

| 

_utmb

_utmc

| 

These cookies work in tandem to calculate visit length. Google __utmb cookie demarks the exact arrival time, then Google __utmc registers the precise exit time of the user.

| 

Google Analytics

| 

_utmt

| 

Used to throttle request rate.

| 

Google Analytics

| 

_utmz

| 

Cookie __utmz monitors the HTTP Referrer and notes where a visitor arrived from, with the referrer siloed into type (Search engine (organic or cpc), direct, social and unaccounted). From the HTTP Referrer the __utmz Cookie also registers, what keyword generated the visit plus geolocation data.

| 

Google Maps

| 

apisid, hsid, nid, pref, sapisid, sid, ssid

| 

Used to measure the number and behaviour of Google Maps users.

| 

Google Tag Manager

| 

_dc_gtm_ua-32824389-1

| 

This cookie allows Google Tag Manager (GTM) to load scripts and code into a page. GTM is used to record analytics data, including number of visits and visit length.

| 

Hotjar

| 

_hjClosedSurveyInvites, _hjDonePolls, _hjMinimizedPolls, _hjDoneTestersWidgets, _hjMinimizedTestersWidgets, _hjDoneSurveys, _hjIncludedInSample, _hjShownFeedbackMessage

| 

Hotjar sets cookies to support their Analysis tools, which allow us to measure and observe user behaviour, and their Feedback tools, which allow us to hear what you have to say.

| 

Hobsons Radius

| 

_ga, _gat_radiusenterpriserollup, jsessionid

| 

This is the Interest Page or data capture page. They are Hobsons hosted pages, designed for the collection of data from enquirers, in order to offer a personalised, timely and relevant user experience via the Interest Pages and or the application.

| 

Recite

| 

recite

| 

Recite only use cookies for a handful of things, which includes:

  * Access tokens - these are a form of session-ID that is used for API requests to validate users, there is no data transferred other than a true or false value
  * Preferences - UI preferences are normally saved on our server but may be stored in a cookie as a fall back if this process fails.
  * Activate Persistance - We use cookie to activate persistence so once a user has activated Recite the bar will remains when they go to another page unless they close the bar.

| 

Siteimprove

| 

_cfduid, asp.net_sessionid, nmstat, siteimproveses

| 

These cookies are used to help record the visitor’s use of the website. They are used to collect statistics about site usage such as when the visitor last visited the site. This information is then used to improve the user experience on the website. These cookies contain no personal information and are used only for web analytics.

| 

Twitter

| 

external_referer, guest_id, k, original_referer, pid, twitter_sess, twll

| 

These cookies are created by Twitter.

York St John uses both Twitter widget or buttons on our website.

| 

YouTube

| 

demographics, hsid, login_info, pref, sid, ssid, use_hotbox, visitor_info1_live, watched_video_id_list

| 

York St John has a YouTube channel and embed our videos into our website using YouTube’s embed code.

You can find out more about the YouTube cookies on their website.

|
